https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_bg
Bulgarian
 Institutsionalnata struktura na Evropeyskiya sayuz e unikalna, a negovata sistema za vzemane na resheniya neprekasnato se razviva. Sedemte evropeyski institutsii, sedemte organa na ES i nad 30 detsentralizirani agentsii sa razpolozheni v tseliya Sayuz. Te rabotyat zaedno, za da otstoyavat obshtite interesi na ES i na evropeyskite grazhdani.  Sashtestvuvat oshte 20 agentsii i organizatsii na ES, koito imat spetsifichni yuridicheski kompetentsii, i 4 mezhduinstitutsionalni sluzhbi, koito podpomagat institutsiite. Vsichki te izpalnyavat spetsifichni roli – ot razrabotvaneto na zakonodatelstvoto i izgotvyaneto na politikite na ES do prilaganeto na politiki i rabotata v spetsializirani oblasti kato zdraveopazvane, meditsina, transport i okolna sreda. Administratsiyata na ES se rakovodi ot 4 osnovni institutsii, koito vzemat resheniya. Tezi institutsii zaedno opredelyat nasokata na politikata na ES i izpalnyavat razlichni roli v zakonodatelniya protses: , Evropeyskiyat parlament (Bryuksel/Strasburg/Lyuksemburg), Evropeyskiyat savet (Bryuksel), Savetat na Evropeyskiya sayuz (Bryuksel/Lyuksemburg), Evropeyskata komisiya (Bryuksel/Lyuksemburg/predstavitelstva v darzhavite ot ES) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_da
Danish
 EU's institutionelle struktur er enestående, og dets beslutningssystem er under konstant udvikling. De 7 EU-institutioner, 7 EU-organer og over 30 decentrale agenturer er spredt over hele EU. De arbejder sammen om at varetage EU's og de europæiske borgeres fælles interesser.  Med hensyn til administration er der yderligere 20 EU-agenturer og -organisationer, som udfører specifikke juridiske funktioner, og 4 interinstitutionelle tjenester, der støtter institutionerne. Alle enhederne har specifikke opgaver – fra udarbejdelse af EU-lovgivning og politikudformning til gennemførelse af politikker og opgaver inden for særlige områder såsom sundhed, lægemidler, transport og miljø. Der er 4 primære institutioner, som har beslutningskompetence, og som varetager ledelsen af EU's administration. Institutionerne udarbejder i fællesskab EU's politiske retningslinjer og har forskellige roller i lovgivningsprocessen: , Europa-Parlamentet (Bruxelles/Strasbourg/Luxembourg), Det Europæiske Råd (Bruxelles), Rådet for Den Europæiske Union (Bruxelles/Luxembourg), Europa-Kommissionen (Bruxelles/Luxembourg/repræsentationer i hele EU) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_de
German
 Die Europäische Union ist in ihrer institutionellen Struktur einzigartig und ihr Beschlussfassungssystem entwickelt sich ständig weiter. Es gibt 7 Organe, 7 Einrichtungen und über 30 dezentrale Agenturen der EU, verteilt in der gesamten Union. In enger Zusammenarbeit verfolgen sie die gemeinsamen Interessen der EU und der europäischen Bevölkerung.  Im administrativen Bereich gibt es zudem noch 20 Agenturen und Organisationen, die spezifische rechtliche Aufgaben wahrnehmen, sowie 4 interinstitutionelle Dienste, die die Organe bei ihrer Arbeit unterstützen. Jede Struktur hat spezifische Aufgaben: Ausarbeitung von EU-Rechtsvorschriften, Politikgestaltung, Umsetzung politischer Maßnahmen oder Tätigkeiten in Fachbereichen wie Gesundheit, Medizin, Verkehr und Umwelt. 4 zentrale Beschlussfassungsorgane prägen die EU-Verwaltung: Sie geben der EU gemeinsam die politische Richtung vor und nehmen im Rechtsetzungsprozess unterschiedliche Rollen ein: , das Europäische Parlament (Brüssel/Straßburg/Luxemburg), der Europäische Rat (Brüssel), der Rat der Europäischen Union (Brüssel/Luxemburg), die Europäische Kommission (Brüssel/Luxemburg/Vertretungen in der gesamten EU) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_en
English
 The European Union’s institutional set-up is unique and its decision-making system is constantly evolving. The 7 European institutions, 7 EU bodies and over 30 decentralised agencies are spread across the EU. They work together to address the common interests of the EU and European people.  In terms of administration, there are a further 20 EU agencies and organisations which carry out specific legal functions and 4 interinstitutional services which support the institutions. All of these establishments have specific roles – from developing EU laws and policy-making to implementing policies and working on specialist areas, such as health, medicine, transport and the environment. There are 4 main decision-making institutions which lead the EU’s administration. These institutions collectively provide the EU with policy direction and play different roles in the law-making process: , the European Parliament (Brussels/Strasbourg/Luxembourg), the European Council (Brussels), the Council of the European Union (Brussels/Luxembourg), the European Commission (Brussels/Luxembourg/Representations across the EU) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_et
Estonian
 Euroopa Liidul on ainulaadne institutsiooniline ülesehitus ning selle otsustussüsteem areneb pidevalt. Üle kogu ELi laiali asuvad seitse Euroopa institutsiooni, seitse ELi organit ja enam kui 30 detsentraliseeritud asutust. Kõik need institutsioonid ja asutused teevad koostööd ELi ja Euroopa kodanike ühiste huvide edendamiseks.  ELi haldussüsteemi täiendavad veel 20 ametit ja organisatsiooni, mis täidavad täpselt määratletud õiguslikke ülesandeid, ning 4 institutsioonidevahelist teenistust, mis institutsioonide tegevust toetavad. Igal institutsioonil ja asutusel on oma ülesanne – alates ELi õigusaktide väljatöötamisest ja poliitika kujundamisest kuni tegevuskavade rakendamise ja valdkondliku ekspertiisini kitsamates valdkondades, nagu tervishoid, meditsiin, transport või keskkond. ELi haldusaparaati juhib neli peamist otsuseid tegevat institutsiooni. Need neli institutsiooni üheskoos määravad kindlaks ELi poliitilise suuna ja osalevad kindlates ülesannetes Euroopa Liidu õigusloomeprotsessis: , Euroopa Parlament (Brüssel/Strasbourg/Luxembourg), Euroopa Ülemkogu (Brüssel), Euroopa Liidu Nõukogu (Brüssel/Luxembourg), Euroopa Komisjon ( Brüssel / Luxembourg / esindused üle kogu ELi) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_fi
Finnish
 Euroopan unionin toimielin- ja päätöksentekojärjestelmä on ainutlaatuinen, ja sitä kehitetään jatkuvasti. EU:lla on 7 toimielintä, 7 muuta elintä ja yli 30 erillisvirastoa, jotka sijaitsevat eri puolilla EU:ta. Yhdessä ne ajavat EU:n ja EU-kansalaisten yhteisiä etuja.  Lisäksi EU:lla on 20 erityistehtäviä hoitavaa virastoa ja elintä sekä 4 toimielinten yhteistä palveluyksikköä. Näillä kaikilla on omat erityistehtävänsä EU:n lainsäädännön ja politiikan suunnittelussa tai toimien täytäntöönpanossa, ja monet niistä ovat erikoistuneet tietyille erikoisaloille, kuten terveysasioihin, lääketieteeseen, liikenteeseen tai ympäristökysymyksiin. EU:n päätöksentekoon osallistuu neljä päätoimielintä, jotka vastaavat yhdessä EU:n toiminnan painopisteistä, ja niillä on omat roolinsa lainsäädäntöprosessissa. Kyseiset elimet ovat: , Euroopan parlamentti (Bryssel/Strasbourg/Luxemburg), Eurooppa-neuvosto (Bryssel), Euroopan unionin neuvosto (Bryssel/Luxemburg), Euroopan komissio (Bryssel/Luxemburg/edustustot eri puolilla EU:ta). 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_fr
French
 La structure institutionnelle de l’Union européenne est unique et son système décisionnel évolue constamment. Les 7 institutions européennes, 7 organes de l’UE et plus de 30 agences décentralisées sont répartis dans l’ensemble de l’UE. Ils œuvrent ensemble pour promouvoir les intérêts communs de l’UE et des citoyens européens.  En ce qui concerne l’administration, 20 autres agences et organismes de l’UE exercent des fonctions juridiques spécifiques et 4 services interinstitutionnels soutiennent les institutions. Tous ces établissements ont des rôles spécifiques, allant de l’élaboration de la législation et des politiques de l’UE à la mise en œuvre des politiques et aux activités dans des domaines spécialisés, tels que la santé, la médecine, les transports et l’environnement. 4 principales institutions décisionnelles dirigent l’administration de l’UE. Ensemble, ces institutions fournissent à l’UE des orientations politiques et jouent des rôles différents dans le processus législatif: , le Parlement européen (Bruxelles/Strasbourg/Luxembourg), le Conseil européen (Bruxelles), le Conseil de l’Union européenne (Bruxelles/Luxembourg), la Commission européenne (Bruxelles/Luxembourg/représentations dans toute l’UE) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_el
Greek
 To thesmiko plaisio tis Europaikis Έnosis einai monadiko kai to systima lipsis apofaseon tis exelissetai sunechos. Ta 7 europaika thesmika organa, ta 7 loipa organa tis EE kai perissoteroi apo 30 apokentromenoi organismoi einai diaskorpismena se olokliri tin EE. Sunergazontai gia tin antimetopisi ton koinon sumferonton tis EE kai ton europaion politon.  Όson afora ti dioikisi, uparchoyn alloi 20 organismoi kai foreis tis EE poy ekteloyn eidika nomika kathikonta kai 4 diorganikes upiresies poy upostirizoyn ta thesmika organa. Όles autes oi ontotites echoyn sugkekrimenoys roloys — apo tin anaptuxi tis nomothesias kai ti charaxis politikis tis EE eos tin efarmogi politikon kai tin ektelesi ergasion se exeidikeumenoys tomeis, opos i ugeia, i iatriki, oi metafores kai to perivallon. Uparchoyn 4 kyria thesmika organa lipsis apofaseon poy igoyntai tis dioikisis tis EE. Ta thesmika auta organa parechoyn apo koinoy stin EE kateuthynseis politikis kai diadramatizoyn diaforetikoys roloys sti nomothetiki diadikasia: , to Europaiko Koinovoylio (Vruxelles/Strasvoyrgo/Loyxemvoyrgo), to Europaiko Sumvoylio (Vruxelles), to Sumvoylio tis Europaikis Έnosis (Vruxelles/Loyxemvoyrgo), i Europaiki Epitropi (Vruxelles/Loyxemvoyrgo/Antiprosopeies se olokliri tin EE) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_ga
Irish
 Is uathúil an leagan amach institiúideach atá ag an Aontas Eorpach agus bíonn a chóras cinnteoireachta ag forbairt de shíor. Tá 7 n-institiúid Eorpacha, 7 gcomhlacht de chuid an Aontais agus os cionn 30 gníomhaireacht dhíláraithe ann ar fud an Aontais Eorpaigh. Bíonn siad ag obair le chéile chun aghaidh a thabhairt ar chomhleasanna an Aontais agus mhuintir na hEorpa.  Ó thaobh an riaracháin de, tá 20 gníomhaireacht agus eagraíocht eile de chuid an Aontais ann a dhéanann feidhmeanna dlíthiúla ar leith, sin agus 4 sheirbhís idirinstitiúideacha a thacaíonn leis na hinstitiúidí. Tá róil shonracha ag na heagraíochtaí sin ar fad, cuir i gcás dlíthe an Aontais a fhorbairt, beartais a cheapadh, beartais a chur chun feidhme agus obair a dhéanamh ar shainréimsí ar nós na sláinte, an leighis, an iompair agus an chomhshaoil. Tá 4 phríomhinstitiúid chinnteoireachta ann atá i gceannas ar riarachán an Aontais. Ag obair dóibh i dteannta a chéile, cuireann na hinstitiúidí sin treoir ar fáil don Aontas maidir le beartais agus is éagsúil na róil atá acu sa phróiseas reachtóireachta: , Parlaimint na hEorpa (an Bhruiséil/Strasbourg/Lucsamburg), an Chomhairle Eorpach (an Bhruiséil), Comhairle an Aontais Eorpaigh (an Bhruiséil/Lucsamburg), an Coimisiún Eorpach (an Bhruiséil/Lucsamburg/Ionadaíochtaí ar fud an Aontais) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_it
Italian
 L'assetto istituzionale dell'Unione europea è unico nel suo genere e il suo sistema decisionale è in costante evoluzione. Le 7 istituzioni europee, 7 organi dell'UE e le oltre 30 agenzie decentrate sono distribuiti in tutta l'UE. Lavorano tutti insieme per tutelare gli interessi comuni dell'UE e dei cittadini europei.  In termini amministrativi, esistono altre 20 agenzie e organizzazioni dell'UE che svolgono funzioni giuridiche specifiche e 4 servizi interistituzionali a sostegno delle istituzioni. Tutti hanno ruoli specifici: dall'elaborazione della legislazione e della definizione delle politiche dell'UE all'attuazione delle politiche e al lavoro in settori specializzati, come la salute, la medicina, i trasporti e l'ambiente. Sono 4 le principali istituzioni decisionali che dirigono l'amministrazione dell'UE e forniscono collettivamente all'UE orientamenti politici, svolgendo ruoli diversi nel processo legislativo: , il Parlamento europeo (Bruxelles / Strasburgo / Lussemburgo), il Consiglio europeo (Bruxelles), il Consiglio dell'Unione europea (Bruxelles / Lussemburgo), la Commissione europea (Bruxelles/Lussemburgo/Rappresentanze in tutta l'UE). 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_lv
Latvian
 Eiropas Savienības institucionālā struktūra ir unikāla, un tās lēmumu pieņemšanas sistēma pastāvīgi attīstās. Septiņas Eiropas iestādes, septiņas ES institūcijas un vairāk nekā 30 decentralizētās aģentūras atrodas visā ES. Cieši sadarbojoties, tās rīkojas atbilstīgi ES un Eiropas iedzīvotāju kopīgajām interesēm.  Administrēšanas jomā ir vēl 20 citas ES aģentūras un organizācijas, kas pilda īpašus juridiskus uzdevumus, kā arī četri starpiestāžu dienesti, kas atbalsta attiecīgās iestādes to darbā. Katrai iestādei ir konkrēts uzdevums: ES tiesību aktu izstrāde, politikas veidošana, politikas pasākumu īstenošana vai darbs tādās specializētās jomās kā veselība, medicīna, transports un vide. Četras galvenās lēmējiestādes īsteno ES pārvaldi. Šīs iestādes kopīgi nodrošina ES politiskās pamatnostādnes, un pilda dažādas lomas likumdošanas procesā: , Eiropas Parlaments (Brisele / Strasbūra / Luksemburga),, Eiropadome (Brisele),, Eiropas Savienības Padome (Brisele / Luksemburga),, Eiropas Komisija ( Brisele / Luksemburga / pārstāvniecības visā ES ). 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_lt
Lithuanian
 Europos Sąjungos institucinė struktūra unikali, o jos sprendimų priėmimo sistema nuolat kinta. Įvairiose ES vietose veikia 7 Europos institucijos, 7 ES įstaigos ir daugiau kaip 30 decentralizuotų agentūrų. Jos dirba išvien, kad spręstų su bendrais ES ir Europos žmonių interesais susijusius klausimus.  Administraciniu požiūriu yra dar 20 ES agentūrų ir organizacijų, atliekančių konkrečias teisines funkcijas, ir 4 tarpinstitucinės tarnybos, padedančios institucijoms. Visos šios tarnybos atlieka konkrečius vaidmenis: nuo ES teisės aktų rengimo bei politikos formavimo iki politikos įgyvendinimo bei darbo specializuotose srityse, pavyzdžiui, sveikatos, medicinos, transporto ir aplinkos. ES administracijai vadovauja 4 pagrindinės sprendimus priimančios institucijos. Šios institucijos kartu nustato ES politikos kryptį ir atlieka skirtingus vaidmenis teisėkūros procese: , Europos Parlamentas (Briuselis/ Strasbūras/ Liuksemburgas), Europos Vadovų Taryba (Briuselis), Europos Sąjungos Taryba (Briuselis/ Liuksemburgas), Europos Komisija (Briuselis/ Liuksemburgas/ atstovybės visoje ES) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_nl
Dutch
 De instellingen van de Europese Unie vormen een uniek samenspel met een besluitvormingssysteem dat voortdurend evolueert. De zeven Europese instellingen, zeven EU-organen en meer dan dertig gedecentraliseerde agentschappen bevinden zich op verschillende plaatsen in de EU. Samen behartigen zij de gemeenschappelijke belangen van de EU en de Europeanen.  Voor het bestuur zijn er daarnaast nog twintig EU-agentschappen en -organisaties met specifieke juridische functies en vier interinstitutionele diensten die de instellingen ondersteuning bieden. Al deze organisaties vervullen een eigen, specifieke rol: zij stellen wetten en beleid op, voeren beleidsmaatregelen uit of zijn gespecialiseerd in bepaalde werkgebieden, zoals gezondheid, geneesmiddelen, vervoer en milieu. De EU wordt bestuurd door vier belangrijke instellingen die de besluitvorming bepalen. Deze instellingen stippelen samen de koers voor het EU-beleid uit, maar spelen elk een andere rol in het wetgevingsproces: , het Europees Parlement (Brussel/Straatsburg/Luxemburg), de Europese Raad (Brussel), de Raad van de Europese Unie (Brussel/Luxemburg), de Europese Commissie (Brussel/Luxemburg/vertegenwoordigingen in de hele EU) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_pl
Polish
 Struktura instytucjonalna Unii Europejskiej jest wyjątkowa, a jej system decyzyjny stale ewoluuje. W całej UE działa 7 instytucji europejskich, 7 organów UE i ponad 30 agencji zdecentralizowanych. Współpracują one ze sobą w celu realizacji wspólnych interesów UE i Europejczyków.  Jeśli chodzi o administrację, istnieje 20 agencji i organizacji UE, które pełnią określone funkcje prawne, oraz 4 służby międzyinstytucjonalne, które wspierają instytucje. Wszystkie te podmioty pełnią określone role – od opracowywania przepisów UE i kształtowania polityki, po wdrażanie polityki i pracę w specjalistycznych dziedzinach, takich jak zdrowie, medycyna, transport i środowisko. Istnieją cztery główne instytucje decyzyjne, które kierują administracją UE. Instytucje te wspólnie określają kierunek polityki UE i odgrywają różne role w procesie stanowienia prawa: , Parlament Europejski (Bruksela/Strasburg/Luksemburg), Rada Europejska (Bruksela), Rada Unii Europejskiej (Bruksela/Luksemburg), Komisja Europejska (Bruksela/Luksemburg/przedstawicielstwa w całej UE) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_pt
Portuguese
 O quadro institucional da União Europeia é único e o seu sistema de tomada de decisões está em constante evolução. As sete instituições europeias, os sete organismos da UE e mais de 30 agências descentralizadas estão descentralizados por toda a UE, mas trabalham em conjunto para abordar os interesses comuns da UE e dos cidadãos europeus.  Em termos de administração, existem mais 20 agências e organizações da UE que desempenham funções jurídicas específicas e quatro serviços interinstitucionais que apoiam as instituições. Todos estes estabelecimentos têm papéis específicos, desde o desenvolvimento da legislação e da elaboração de políticas da UE até à aplicação de políticas e ao trabalho em domínios especializados, como a saúde, a medicina, os transportes e o ambiente. Existem quatro principais instituições de decisão que dirigem a administração da UE. Estas instituições proporcionam coletivamente à UE orientações políticas e desempenham diferentes papéis no processo legislativo: , Parlamento Europeu (Bruxelas/Estrasburgo/Luxemburgo), Conselho Europeu (Bruxelas), Conselho da União Europeia (Bruxelas/Luxemburgo), Comissão Europeia (Bruxelas/Luxemburgo/Representações em toda a UE) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_ro
Romanian
 Cadrul instituțional al Uniunii Europene este unic, iar sistemul său decizional evoluează în permanență. Cele 7 instituții europene, 7 organisme ale UE și peste 30 de agenții descentralizate sunt răspândite în întreaga UE. Ele lucrează împreună pentru a promova interesele comune ale Uniunii și ale cetățenilor europeni.  În ceea ce privește administrația, există alte 20 de agenții și organizații ale UE care îndeplinesc funcții juridice specifice și 4 servicii interinstituționale care sprijină instituțiile. Toate aceste entități au roluri specifice – de la elaborarea legislației și a politicilor UE până la punerea în aplicare a politicilor și desfășurarea de activități în domenii specializate, cum ar fi sănătatea, medicina, transporturile și mediul. Există 4 instituții decizionale principale care conduc administrația UE. Împreună, aceste instituții îi oferă UE orientări politice și joacă diferite roluri în procesul legislativ: , Parlamentul European (Bruxelles/Strasbourg/Luxemburg), Consiliul European (Bruxelles), Consiliul Uniunii Europene (Bruxelles/Luxemburg), Comisia Europeană (Bruxelles/Luxemburg/Reprezentanțele din întreaga UE) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_sv
Swedish
 EU har ett unikt system av institutioner och organ som deltar i beslutsfattandet på olika sätt. Det finns sju EU-institutioner, sju EU-organ och över 30 decentraliserade byråer som är spridda över hela EU. Tillsammans arbetar de för EU:s och invånarnas gemensamma intressen.  Det finns också ytterligare 20 byråer och organisationer med rättsliga funktioner och fyra gemensamma tjänster som stöder institutionerna i deras arbete. Alla har de sina särskilda uppgifter – från att ta fram EU:s lagar och politik till att genomföra initiativ när det gäller hälsa, medicin, transporter, miljö och andra områden. EU har fyra viktiga beslutsfattande institutioner som slår fast EU:s prioriteringar och medverkar i lagstiftningsarbetet på olika sätt: , Europaparlamentet – Bryssel, Strasbourg och Luxemburg, Europeiska rådet – Bryssel, Europeiska unionens råd (ministerrådet) – Bryssel och Luxemburg, Europeiska kommissionen – Bryssel, Luxemburg och representationskontor i EU 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_sk
Slovak
 Inštitucionálne usporiadanie Európskej únie je jedinečné a jej systém rozhodovania sa neustále vyvíja. Po celej EÚ je rozmiestnených sedem európskych inštitúcií, sedem orgánov EÚ a vyše 30 decentralizovaných agentúr. Spolupracujú na zohľadňovaní spoločných záujmov EÚ a európskych občanov.  Pokiaľ ide o administratívu, funguje ďalších 20 agentúr a organizácií EÚ, ktoré plnia osobitné právne funkcie, a štyri medziinštitucionálne služby, ktoré podporujú inštitúcie. Všetky tieto organizácie majú osobitné úlohy – od tvorby práva a politík EÚ až po vykonávanie politík a prácu v rámci špecializovaných oblastí, ako sú napríklad zdravie, lieky, doprava a životné prostredie. Administratívu EÚ riadia štyri hlavné inštitúcie s rozhodovacou právomocou. Tieto inštitúcie spoločne udávajú EÚ politické smerovanie a zohrávajú rôzne úlohy v procese tvorby práva: , Európsky parlament (Brusel/Štrasburg/Luxemburg), Európska rada (Brusel), Rada Európskej únie (Brusel/Luxemburg), Európska komisia (Brusel/Luxemburg/zastúpenia naprieč EÚ) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_sl
Slovenian
 Institucionalna ureditev Evropske unije je edinstvena, njen sistem odločanja pa se nenehno razvija. Sedem evropskih institucij, sedem organov EU in več kot 30 decentraliziranih agencij je razpredenih po vsej EU. Skupaj sodelujejo pri obravnavi skupnih interesov EU in evropskih državljanov.  Z administrativnega vidika obstaja še dodatnih 20 agencij in organizacij EU, ki opravljajo posebne pravne funkcije in štiri medinstitucionalne storitve, ki podpirajo institucije. Vse ustanove imajo določene naloge − od oblikovanja prava in politike EU do izvajanja politik in dela na specialističnih področjih, kot so zdravje, medicina, promet in okolje. Upravo EU vodijo štiri glavne institucije, ki sprejemajo odločitve. Te institucije skupaj usmerjajo politiko EU in imajo različne vloge v zakonodajnem postopku: , Evropski parlament (Bruselj/Strasbourg/Luxembourg), Evropski svet (Bruselj), Svet Evropske Unije (Bruselj/Luxembourg), Evropska komisija (Bruselj/Luxembourg/Predstavništva po EU) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_es
Spanish
 El marco institucional de la Unión Europea es único, y su sistema de toma de decisiones está en constante evolución. Las siete instituciones europeas, los siete órganos de la UE y más de treinta agencias descentralizadas se extienden por toda la Unión. Todos ellos trabajan juntos para abordar los intereses comunes de la Unión y de los ciudadanos europeos.  Desde el punto de vista administrativo, hay otras veinte agencias y organismos de la UE que desempeñan funciones jurídicas específicas y cuatro servicios interinstitucionales que prestan apoyo a las instituciones. Todos estos entes tienen cometidos específicos, desde la elaboración de la legislación y la formulación de las políticas de la Unión hasta la aplicación de estas y el trabajo en ámbitos especializados como la sanidad, la medicina, el transporte y el medio ambiente. Hay cuatro instituciones principales responsables de la toma de decisiones que dirigen la administración de la UE. Estas instituciones proporcionan colectivamente orientación política a la UE y desempeñan distintas funciones en el proceso legislativo: , el Parlamento Europeo (Bruselas/Estrasburgo/Luxemburgo);, el Consejo Europeo (Bruselas);, el Consejo de la Unión Europea (Bruselas/Luxemburgo);, la Comisión Europea (Bruselas/Luxemburgo/Representaciones en los Estados miembros). 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_cs
Czech
 Institucionální uspořádání Evropské unie je ojedinělé a její rozhodovací systém se neustále vyvíjí. Po celé Unii je rozmístěno 7 evropských orgánů, 7 institucí EU a více než 30 decentralizovaných agentur, které spolupracují při plnění společných zájmů EU a jejích obyvatel.  Pokud jde o administrativu, existuje dalších 20 agentur a organizací EU, jež vykonávají specifické právní funkce, a 4 interinstitucionální služby, které pomáhají orgánům a institucím správně fungovat. Všechny tyto subjekty mají svou zvláštní úlohu – od vypracování právních předpisů a politických opatření EU až po jejich uvádění do praxe a práci ve specializovaných oblastech, jako je zdravotnictví, doprava či životní prostředí. Správu EU řídí 4 hlavní orgány s rozhodovací pravomocí, které společně stanoví politický směr Unie. V procesu tvorby právních předpisů pak hrají různou úlohu: , Evropský parlament (Brusel/Štrasburk/Lucemburk), Evropská rada (Brusel), Rada Evropské unie (Brusel/Lucemburk), Evropská komise (Brusel/Lucemburk/Zastoupení v zemích EU) 
---------
https://european-union.europa.eu/institutions-law-budget/institutions-and-bodies/types-institutions-and-bodies_hu
Hungarian
 Az Európai Unió intézményi felépítése egyedülálló, döntéshozatali rendszere pedig folyamatosan fejlődik. A 7 európai intézmény, 7 uniós szerv és több mint 30 decentralizált ügynökség különböző székhelyeken működik az Európai Unió területén. Egymással együttműködve azon dolgoznak, hogy érvényre juttassák az EU és az uniós polgárok közös érdekeit.  Ezenfelül 20 uniós ügynökség és szervezet, valamint 4 intézményközi szolgálat működik adminisztratív területen. Előbbiek konkrét jogi feladatokat látnak el, míg az utóbbiak az intézmények tevékenységét támogatják. Az uniós intézmények, szervek és ügynökségek mindegyikének megvan a maga sajátos szerepe – az uniós jogszabályok és szakpolitikák kidolgozásától kezdve a szakpolitikák végrehajtásáig és a különböző szakterületeken – pl. az egészségügy, az orvostudomány, a közlekedés és a környezetvédelem terén – végzett munkáig. Az EU igazgatási struktúrájának élén négy fő döntéshozó intézményt találunk. Ezek az intézmények közösen alakítják ki az uniós szakpolitikák irányvonalát, és eltérő szerepet töltenek be a jogalkotási folyamatban: , az Európai Parlament (Brüsszel/Strasbourg/Luxembourg), az Európai Tanács (Brüsszel), az Európai Unió Tanácsa (Brüsszel/Luxembourg), az Európai Bizottság (Brüsszel/Luxembourg/az EU-tagállamokban működő képviseletek) 
---------
